<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UniFi on ajh123&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://ajh123.github.io/tags/unifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UniFi on ajh123&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:21:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ajh123.github.io/tags/unifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Which Vlans UniFi Teleport Can Use</title>
      <link>https://ajh123.github.io/post/controlling-which-vlans-unifi-teleport-can-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajh123.github.io/post/controlling-which-vlans-unifi-teleport-can-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guide we will learn how to configure which IPs and VLANs users connected via UniFi Teleport can access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-identify-the-ip-range-that-teleport-uses&#34;&gt;Step 1. Identify the IP range that Teleport uses.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to know who we are controlling we need the know the IP range. One way to find this is to inspect a device connected with UniFi Teleport.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do this, open the Network app and navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Client Devices&lt;/strong&gt;. On this page you will find a list of all the clients and their IP address. Clients that are connected with UniFi Teleport will have the connection type of &amp;ldquo;VPN&amp;rdquo;. In Figure 1 you can see I have two devices one with the IP &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;192.168.2.3&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;192.168.2.2&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;, so, the subnet for this Teleport instance would be &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;192.168.2.0/24&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UniFi Vpn With Active Directory and Radius</title>
      <link>https://ajh123.github.io/post/unifi-vpn-with-active-directory-and-radius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajh123.github.io/post/unifi-vpn-with-active-directory-and-radius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guide we will set up a VPN on a UniFi network that uses a RADIUS server that is backed by Active Directory for authentication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-set-up-a-radius-server&#34;&gt;Step 1. Set up a RADIUS server&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use RADIUS for authentication, you must have a RADIUS server configured.&#xA;The RADIUS server built into UniFi cannot be configured to use Active Directory, so an external RADIUS server is required.&#xA;Here is a list of potential RADIUS servers you can use:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
